# **MISHAL SHAH**

Email: mishalshah92@gmail.com Phone: (+91)7600454376 Web: www.ms92.in LinkedIn: in/mishalshah92

#### **SUMMARY**

Versatile DevOps Engineer with 4.5 years of experience. Starting as a java developer, having experience of both coding and administration. Experienced to work into various function of the DevOps like Dev Productivity, Site Reliability, Automation, Release Engineering. Experienced to design and develop the end-to-end service with cloud-integration and having expertise to architect the server less solutions.

# **SKILLS**

- DevOps, Containers, Docker, Micro-services
- AWS, GCP, Azure
- Jenkins, Bamboo, Git, Bitbucket, GitLab
- Terraform, Cloud-formation, Chef
- Java, Python, Node, Bash, HTML5, CSS, JS, JSON, Ajax, jQuery
- Spring Boot, Hibernate
- Apache 2, Tomcat
- Maven, Gradle
- Logic Monitor, Grafana, CloudWatch, Sitre24x7
- Logz.io, ELK Stack
- MySQL, Dynamo DB, Redshift

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Software Engineer - DevOps**

Feb 2018 - Present

Sophos (Formerly Known as Cyberoam Technologies Private Limited), Ahmedabad, Gujarat, IN

- Writing automations using Python, bash, Terraform, Cloud-formation, Chef, that build infrastructure over cloud.
- Developing and maintaining the infra libraries into Terraform that enables quick deployment of the infrastructure following the company practices.
- Creating base images, development, test and release ready artefacts composing multi-container environments.
- Implementing automated test, build, release and deployment using Jenkins and bamboo integrating with GitHub, Bitbucket, GitLab.
- Building Continuous Integration/Continuous Delivery systems using Jenkins pipeline plugin and other tools.
- Performing end-to-end administration of AWS infrastructure, focusing on Linux based systems.
- Maintaining system upgrades including service packs, patches, hot fixes, vulnerabilities, and security configuration.
- Collaboratively working with software engineering team to deploy micro-services with EC2, ECS, Docker.
- Upgrading and maintaining service templates that enable the secure deployment of the micro-services implementing the best practices.
- Taking part into the architecture review to evaluate design and architecture.
- Using monitoring as code to reflect the metrics such as jvm metrics for java service and infra to monitoring dashboards at Grafana, Logic monitor.
- Documenting troubleshooting guide run-books for quick resolution on occurrence of issue.
- Taking part into on call process for issue troubleshooting and resolution.
- Writing automations using Java, Python, bash that perform the automated issue resolve.
- Taking part into the migration practice for the cloud resources from various services.

DevOps Engineer May 2017 – Dec 2017

Quantiphi, Mumbai, Maharashtra, IN

- Handling and managing the AWS and GCP cloud for over 200+ team members.
- As the first DevOps, define DevOps practice for the Company and help team to implement practice.
- Review and influence new and evolving design, architecture, standards, and methods for operating services and systems.
- Develop scalable infrastructure components and tools for infrastructure monitoring.
- Managing DevOps tools GIT-GitLab repository, Jenkins CI/CD.
- Building automation for quick infrastructure deployment and monitoring.
- Built an automation for cloud resource utilization that save the cost of the company up-to \$1000/ year.
- Built automation to implement the secure usage of the cloud resources.

#### **Cost Measure Manager**

Write an automation that was scheduled to measure the cost of running infrastructure with major two insights one is to measure total Cost of running infrastructure for each Client and other is, Infrastructure utilization against its sizing. Automation is capable to list the resources with its utilization and identity. Automation was capable to read resources for various cloud services such as EC2, RDS, Load-balancing, DynamoDB, Redshift, etc.

KEYWORDWS: Java, Lambda, CloudWatch Trigger and logs, Tags management, AWS Java API.

### **Secure Manager**

Secure manages is an automation that was taking care the basic security practice as below.

- Managing source of Inbound traffic for security groups.
- ELB Traffic measure.
- Data Download and Upload from S3.
- Resource Deletions events.

Automation was built with the serverless that trigger based on the CloudTrail event and execute the lambda based on the event which will execute and implement the necessary action to prevent the further action. It also generates the notification to the resource owner and the DevOps.

KEYWORDWS: Java, Lambda, SNS, CloudTrail Events, CloudWatch Trigger and logs, AWS Java API.

## **Software Engineer - DevOps**

Sep 2014 – Apr 2017

SoftVan, Ahmedabad, Gujarat, IN

- Writing the cloud-ready application using AWS Cloud API that integrate the AWS services such as S3, DynamoDB, Redshift, Cognito, etc.
- Deploying and managed the application deployment over the AWS cloud with services EC2, ELB, Autoscaling, RDS, DynamoDB, Redshift.
- Integrating AWS Cognito for the platform independent authentication and authorization.
- Design and Developed the media processing services using the AWS Elastic Transcoder services which serverless processing implementation using AWS lambda, AWS RDS, AWS SNS.

## **TASKTOWER Document Management (www.deepfoods.com)**

Design the serverless document management service that allows the employees to create, upload, download, share documents. The challenge was to build the document management service with the serverless that operate with the AWS Lambda and store the files to the AWS S3. Build sync application desktop apps for Windows and android consuming same serverless backend.

**KEYWORDWS:** AWS S3, AWS Lambda, AWS RDS, AWS API Gateway, AWS SNS, Java, HTML, CSS, JS, JSON, AJAX, Multipart upload, sharing with access level management, synchronization, Encryption, versioning.

# **NAIL-BITER** (nail-biter.com)

Company running video campaigning portal serving to thousands of customers. From the millions of devices companying videos got uploaded to the Server. Build the server less architecture for video compression, scheduled backups watermarking, web-services, with disaster recovery.

KEYWORDWS: AWS S3, AWS ETS, AWS RDS, AWS SNS, AWS Cognito

#### TREAND ANALYSIS

Every day there is new research in the world. Challenge is to gather the research that is going on around the world and to process it for finding treading technology. Gather patents form almost around the world's patent office and process it to generate trend analytic. We developed dynamic approach that process patents and generate the analytic with real-time updating scenario.

KEYWORDWS: NLP, AWS EC2, AWS S3, AWS Redshift, Java, HTML, CSS, JS, JSON, AJAX

#### **GPS TRAJECTORY MATCHING**

**CHALLENGE:** The location tracking into the vehicle with the GPS devices and the mobile app for the human location tracing. GPS tracking data for both the vehicles and human are continuously coming and will store to database. Challenge is to find weather person was into the vehicle or not.

**SOLUTION:** Designed queuing solution with AWS, to process the continuous data with SQS, S3, and RDS. We work on the algorithm named Dynamic Time Warping to match the locations. We configured the advance custom log management with AWS S3 for storing.

KEYWORDWS: Dynamic Time Warping (DTW), AWS EC2, AWS S3, AWS RDS, AWS SQS, Java

## **EDUCATION**

B.E. Computer from Gujarat Technological University (GTU), 2010 – 2014

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Diploma in Java by C-DAC.
- Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals
- Essential Cloud Infrastructure
  - Core
  - o Foundation
  - Scaling and Automation

#### **LANGUAGES**

- English (Professional)
- Hindi (National)
- Gujarati (Native)